A Guide to the Prentis Family Papers, 1742-1828.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Papers, 1742-1828.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 75.2
1 vol. and 9 items.
Prentis Family.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1975.
Alternative Form
Microfilm copy (M-1317.1) available.
Biographical/Historical Information
John Prentis (1729-1775) was a Williamsburg merchant; Robert was his cousin. Robert later moved to Trinidad and died there. Joseph Prentis (1782-1851) was a lawyer in Suffolk and the son of Judge Joseph Prentis (1754-1809) Williamsburg.
Scope and Content Information
Ledger of accounts receivable of the Prentis Store dating from about 1778, including a list of bad debts from 1742. The account book seems to be by Robert Prentis (1741-ca.1809) of the firm of John Prentis and Company. The firm became Robert Prentis and Company during 1775-1779. Names in the account book include Carter Braxton, Nathaniel Burwell, Christiana Campbell, Landon Carter, Robert Carter, Josiah Chowning, Benjamin Harrison, Thomas Jefferson, John Page, Peyton Randolph, William Randolph, and George Wythe. The nine pieces are notes or accounts to Joseph Prentis from John Giles, Henry W. Wills, Thaddeus Powell, and Merrit Jordan, dated 1813 to 1828.
Arrangement
Items are arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Persons:
Braxton, Carter, 1736-1797.; Burwell, Nathaniel, 1750-1814.; Campbell, Christiana, 1722-1793.; Carter, Landon, 1710-1778.; Carter, Robert, 1728- 1804.; Chowning, Josiah, d. 1772.; Giles, John.; Harrison, Benjamin, ca. 1726-1791.; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826.; Jordan, Merrit.; Page, John, 1744-1808.; Powell, Thaddeus.; Prentis, Joseph, 1754-1809.; Prentis, Robert, d. 1803.; Randolph, Peyton, 1721-1775.; Wythe, George, 1726-1806.; Willis, Henry W.
Corporate Names:
John Prentis & Co.; Robert Prentis & Co.; Prentis Store (Williamsburg, Va.)
Geographical Names:
Williamsburg (Va.) --History --Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.; Williamsburg (Va.) --People --18th Century.; Williamsburg (Va.) --People --19th Century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Account books --Virginia.; Merchant accounts - -Virginia -- History --18th Century.; Merchant accounts --Virginia --History --19th Century.
Contents List
- Account book of accounts receivable of the Prentis Store, probably from about 1778 - includes a list of Bad Debts from 1742. 1778.
- Note. John Giles to Joseph Prentis. 2 August 1813.
- Account of Henry W. Wills of Isle of Wight. 1816.
- Account of Henry W. Wills, Jr., administrator of Emanuel Wills. 24 April 1817.
- Account of Henry W. Wills. 1817.
- Account of Henry W. Wills, administrator of John S. Wills, to Joseph Prentis. August 1817.
- Account of Thaddeus Powell to Joseph Prentis. 1827.
- Note. Merrit Jordan to Joseph Prentis. 5 March 1828.
- Account. Joseph Prentis vs. Henry W. Wills. N.D.
- Printed note form. N.D.